KALEB TSEGAYE

Adelphi, MD ♦ 240-688-8166 ♦ kalebtseg@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/kalebts ♦ LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kaleb-tsegaye

SUMMARY

Writing code to simplify workflows or detect relationships within a dataset are tasks I find gratifying. My background as a formally trained spatial data specialist has primed me for data visualization and analysis, so building on that with new concepts and tools is befitting.

TECHNICAL SKILLS/TOOLS

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, HTML/CSS, Javascript, R

Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Geopandas, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Streamlit, LeafletJS, Selenium

GIS Software: ArcGIS, ArcGIS Pro, QGIS, ENVI

PROJECTS

Synth Parameter Estimator

May 2022 – June 2022

 A Streamlit app that takes an audio sample of a synth being played as input, and provides predictions for basic waveforms and the amplitude envelope using several convolutional neural networks

Ames, Iowa Housing Analysis

April 2022

 An analysis of the housing market in Ames, lowa including data cleaning, exploratory data analysis, and multiple regression modeling, told through several Jupyter notebooks

Get a Room UMD February 2019 – April 2019

• An interactive map made with the Javascript library LeafletJS, that displays rooms in academic buildings that are not in use based on the University of Maryland's class schedule

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

Data Science Fellow March 2022 – June 2022

Full-time program with regularly assigned projects covering statistics/machine learning concepts such as
exploratory data analysis, regression analysis, natural language processing, and deep learning

ASRC Federal Suitland, MD (Census Bureau)

GIS Technician I

March 2020 – September 2020

- Digitized and reshaped boundary changes for cities while maintaining underlying layers for the US Census Bureau's Boundary and Annexation Survey
- Assessed and fixed geographic errors in county map files for the US Census Bureau's GARP project in accordance with the program's guidelines

University of Maryland, Facilities Management

College Park, MD

Web GIS Intern

June 2019 – December 2019

- Redesigned popups for the campus web map through the ArcGIS JavaScript API
- Programmed new functionality, such as computing closest parking lots to buildings and extracting
 information from the WMATA API to display in public transportation popups

EDUCATION

General Assembly

March 2022 - June 2022

Data Science Certificate

University of Maryland, College Park

August 2015 - December 2019

College of Behavioral and Social Sciences
Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Science